Let's see exactly how a high-pass filter works.
我们看看高通滤波器到底是如何工作的
I mentioned that high pass filters detect big changes in intensity over a small area,
我之前提过 高通滤波器可以探测小范围内色饱和度的剧烈变化
and patterns of intensity can be best seen in a grayscale image.
色饱和度团在灰阶图像中表现最好
For example, if we put this image of a car through a high-pass filter,
例如 如果我们把这幅汽车的图像放入一个高通滤波器
we expect the edges of the car to be detected,
我们期待汽车的边缘会被探测到
like the edge at the top of the car.
比如汽车顶部的边缘
At this point, the image goes from a very light area on the car to a dark background.
在这个点上 图像从非常亮的区域进入了神色背景
And there are a lot of small areas like this
还有很多类似的小区域
that change from light to dark and vice versa.
从较亮的变为暗色区域 或是反向变化的
The complete filtered image might look like this,
经过滤波后 完整的图像应该是这样的
with the edges of the car and road lines emphasized in white.
汽车的边缘和道路上的线用白色标出
You can also see where there's no change or
你还可以看到原始图像中
little change in intensity in the original picture,
色饱和度没有或几乎没有变化的地方
such as in these large areas of dark and light.
比如 这些大片黑色和明亮区域
A high-pass filter will block these areas out and turn the pixels black.
高通滤波器会屏蔽这些区域 把像素变黑
The filters I'll be talking about are in the form of matrices,
我使用的滤波器形式上是矩阵
often called convolution kernels,
它们通常叫做卷积核
which are just grids of numbers that modify an image.
它们是由数字组成的网格 可以修改图像
Here's an example of a high-pass filter that does edge detection.
下面是执行边缘探测的一个高通滤波器的例子
It's a three by three kernel whose elements all sum to zero.
它是一个 3 乘 3 的核 所有元素相加等于 0
It's important that for edge detection,
这一点对边缘探测很重要
all of the elements sum to zero,
所有元素总和等于 0
because this filter is computing the difference or change between neighboring pixels.
因为这个滤波器计算的是相邻像素之间的差别或变化
Differences are calculated by subtracting pixel values from one another.
差别的计算方法是 像素值之间相减
In this case, subtracting the value of the pixels that surround a center pixel.
在本例中 我们减去围绕在中心像素的其他像素值
And if these kernel values do not add up to zero,
如果这些核的值加起来不等于 0
that would mean that this calculated difference will be
则说明计算出的结果
either positively or negatively weighted,
可能是正加权或负加权的
and this would have the effect of lightening or darkening the entire filtered image.
这可能导致整个滤波后的图像偏亮或偏暗
To apply this filter and input image,
要应用这个滤波器 在输入图像上
which I'll call F(x,
我把它叫做 F(x,y)
y) for a function of x and y space,
这是一个 x 和 y 空间的函数
is convolved with this kernel,
对这个函数使用这个核进行卷积
which I'll call K. This is called kernel convolution,
这个核叫做 K 这个过程叫做核卷积
and convolution is represented by an asterisk,
卷积用星号表示
not to be mistaken for multiplication.
不要和乘法搞混
Kernel convolution is an important operation in computer vision applications,
核卷积是计算机视觉应用里的重要运算
and it's the basis for convolutional neural networks.
它是卷积神经网络的基础
It involves taking a kernel,
它需要有一个核
which is our small grid of numbers,
也就是由数字组成的小网格
and passing it over an image pixel by pixel,
然后把它逐个像素地传递到一幅图像上
creating another edge detected output image based on what these numbers in the grid are.
从而根据网格中的数字 创建另一个探测出边缘的输出图像
And we'll see that by changing the numbers in our kernel,
我们会看到 变更核中的数字后
we can create many different effects from edge detection to blurring in image.
我们能获得很多效果 从边缘探测到模糊化
I walk through a mathematical example using this through by three edged detection filter.
下面 我们使用这个 3 乘 3 的边缘探测器 来解一个数学例子
To better see the pixel level operations,
为了更清楚地看到像素级的运算
I'll zoom in on this image right around
我放大图像 就在
this edge of the car to see the grayscale pixel values.
汽车边缘这里 查看灰阶的像素值
First, for every pixel in this grayscale image,
首先 对于这个灰阶图像中的每一个像素
we put our kernel over it so that a pixel aligns with the center of the kernel.
我们都在上面应用一个核 让这个像素和核的中心对齐
I'm just using this pixel as an example.
这个像素作为一个例子
Then, we look at the three by three grid of pixels centered around this one pixel.
然后 我们查看围绕这个像素的 3 乘 3 的像素网格
We then take the numbers in our kernel and
然后我们取核中的数字
multiply them with their corresponding pixel in pairs.
把它们和对应的像素分对相乘
So this pixel value in the top left corner,150,
这样 左上角的这个像素值 150
is multiplied by the kernel corner zero.
乘以核的左上角数字 0
And next to that, we multiply the value of 45 by negative one.
旁边 我们把数字 45 乘以负 1
And the next,25 by zero.
接下来 25 乘以 0
And then we move on to the next row,
然后我们移到下一行
and we do this for all nine pixel kernel value pairs.
对所有 9 个像素和的值对同样操作
Notice that the center pixel with a value of 200 will be multiplied by four.
注意 中心像素的值 200 会乘以 4
Finally, these values are all summed up to get a new pixel value, 175.
最后 这些值求和 得到了一个新的像素值 175
A high value like this means a pretty strong edge has been detected,
这个值很高 说明检测到了一个很强的边缘
which we can see just by looking at this three by three area in the image.
我们查看图像中的这个 3 乘 3 区域就可以看到
It changes from very light to darker on top.
它从非常亮变为了顶部的深色
The multipliers in the kernel are often called weights because they determine how
核中的因子经常被叫做权重 因为它们决定了
important or how weighty a pixel is in forming a new output image.
像素在形成新的输出图像过程中的重要性或权重
In this case for edge detection,
在本边缘探测的案例中
the center pixel is the most important,
中心像素是最重要的
followed by its closest pixels on the top and bottom and to its left and right.
然后才是顶部、底部和左右两侧距离最近的像素
These are negative weights that increase the contrast in the image.
它们的权重为负 增加了图像的对比度
The corners are the farthest away from the center pixel.
四个角落距离中心像素最远
And in this example, we don't give them any weight.
在本例中 没有赋予它们任何权重
So this weighted some, 175,
因此 这个权重的求和 175
becomes the value for the corresponding pixel at the same location,
就变成了输出图像中相同的 x y 位置的
xy, in the output image,
对应像素的值
and you perform this convolution step for
对原始图像中每个像素位置
every pixel position in the original image until you
执行这个卷积步骤 直到
have a complete output image that's about the same size as
得到完整的输出图像 其大小和输入图像
the input image with new filtered pixel values.
差不多一样 但图像中的像素值为滤波后的值
The only other thing you need to consider is what to do at the edges of
唯一需要考虑的一件事情是 在图像的边缘
your image since the kernel cannot be nicely laid over three by three pixel values.
需要做什么 因为核无法很好地堆积在 3 乘 3 的值上
Next, let's get a little more practice with these kinds of high-pass filters,
下面 我们对这些高通滤波器类型再多做点练习
then get into coding our own.
然后开始编写自己的代码